A Guide to the United Way of Greater Richmond /Richmond Community records 1911-1987
Virginia Commonwealth University, James Branch Cabell Library
Special Collections and Archives, James Branch Cabell Library, Virginia Commonwealth University
United Way of Greater Richmond /Richmond Community records 1911-1987
Special Collections and Archives, James Branch Cabell Library, Virginia Commonwealth University
M 247
25.5 linear feet
United Way of Greater Richmond
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for use without restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Donated to the Department by William F. Wright of the United Way in 1987.
Biographical/Historical Information
The Richmond Area Community Council began in 1911. In 1924 it created the Community Fund, a community-wide trust, to consolidate the fund-raising efforts of area charitable organizations, like the YWCA and Associated Charities (later the Family Service Society). During World War II, the Community Fund became the Richmond War and Community Fund, and after the war the Richmond Community Chest.
In 1974, the Richmond Area Community Council announced the merger of the Council with the United Way.
Scope and Content Information
The collection consists of correspondence, meeting minutes, budgets, committee files, newsletters, and various other materials related to the operation of this organization. In addition, scrapbooks reveal the activities of the organization, and photographs of past presidents of the Richmond Community Council.
Arrangement
The materials are arranged alphabetically by subject, then arranged chronologiaclly where applicable. The oversized scrapbooks are numbered separately.
Contents List
- Accounting Standards 1976 (Box 1)
- Administration 1975-1976 (Box 1)
- Advisory Committee 1956-1957 (Box 1)
- Advisory Committee-Meeting Reservations 1956-1957 (Box 1)
- Advisory Committee-Membership 1957-1958 (Box 1)
- Advisory Committee-Membership Committee 1958-1959 (Box 1)
- Advisory Committee-Membership Sub Committee 1956-1957 (Box 1)
- Advisory Committee-Minutes 1956-1959, 1982 (Box 1)
- Advisory Committee-Office and Office Procedure Sub Committee 1956-1959 (Box 2)
- Advisory Committee of the Volunteer Service Bureau-Special (Study Report) 1973 (Box 2)
- Advisory Committee-Orientation 1956-1958 (Box 2)
- Advisory Committee-Orientation Kit 1957-1958 (Box 2)
- Advisory Committee-Planning and by-laws 1958-1959 (Box 2)
- Advisory Committee-Planning and by-laws Sub Committee 1956-1957 (Box 2)
- Advisory Committee-Planning Committee 1957-1958 (Box 2)
- Advisory Committee-Public Relations Committee 1956-1959 (Box 2)
- Advisory Committee-Recognition Sub Committee 1956-1959 (Box 2)
- Advisory Committee-Recruitment 1957-1959 (Box 3)
- Advisory Committee-Recruitment/College Students 1956-1957 (Box 3)
- Advisory Committee-Recruitment/Students 1957-1959 (Box 3)
- Advisory Committee-Secretary's Report as Given at Meetings 1958-1959 (Box 3)
- Advisory Committee-Standards and Eligibility 1956-1959 (Box 3)
- Advisory Committee-Steering Committee 1957-1958 (Box 3)
- Advisory Council 1982 (Box 3)
- Agency Evaluation Committee 1971 (Box 3)
- Agency Evaluation Committee 1972, 1980 (Box 4)
- Agency Operations Department-Composition and Functions 1970 (Box 4)
- Agency Relations Manual 1975 (Box 4)
- Agency Tax Correspondence 1963 (Box 4)
- Agency Tax Correspondence from Frank Cleaver 1962 (Box 4)
- Agency Tax Procedure 1962 (Box 4)
- Aging-Committee on 1958-1959 (Box 4)
- A Guide to Health Care Resources 1980 (Box 4)
- American Red Cross 1957 (Box 4)
- American Red Cross-Budget 1981-1982 (Box 4)
- American Volunteer 1974 (Box 4)
- Annual Meeting April 23, 1959 (Box 4)
- Annual Meeting and Nominating Committee 1972 (Box 4)
- Annual Report 1956 (Box 4)
- Annual Report 1957-1959, 1963-1967, 1987 (Box 5)
- Annual Report-Other Agencies 1956-1957 (Box 5)
- Applications 1957-1958 (Box 5)
- A Review of the Filer Commission Findings and Recommendations 1975 (Box 5)
- Articles of Incorporation and By-Laws 1971-1976 (Box 5)
- Association of Volunteer Service Bureaus 1957-1959 (Box 5)
- Awards 1976 (Box 5)
- Big Sisters 1956-1957 (Box 5)
- Birthday Party 1957-1958 (Box 5)
- Black and White Potential Volunteers 1976 (Box 5)
- Blue Cross/Blue Shield 1975-1976 (Box 5)
- Blue Ridge 1972 (Box 5)
- Blue Ridge Conference 1972 (Box 5)
- Board Members 1948 (Box 5)
- Board of Directors 1963-1967, 1972 (Box 6)
- Board of Trustees/Directors-Lists 1972-1974 (Box 6)
- Boards 1956-1957 (Box 6)
- Branch House 1955-1973 (Box 6)
- Branch House Employees 1972 (Box 6)
- Branch House Gardens 1974-1976 (Box 6)
- Branch House-Tax Situation 1954-1956 (Box 6)
- Branch House-Tax Situation 1960 (Box 6)
- Branch House-Tax Situation 1961 (Box 6)
- Branch House-Tax Situation 1962 (Box 6)
- Branch Memorial House-Old Copies of Tour Guide (Box 6)
- Branch Memorial House-Segal 1963 (Box 7a)
- Branch Memorial House-Taxes 1958-1960 (Box 7a)
- Brown, Delmar 1972 (Box 7a)
- Budget 1975 (Box 7a)
- Budget and Allocations Committee-Supplemental Request 1977-1980 (Box 7a)
- Budget Committee Minutes, Richmond Community Fund (RCF) 1924-1928 (Box 7a)
- Budget Committee Minutes, RCF 1928-1934 (Box 7a)
- Budget Committee Minutes, RCF 1935-1944 (Box 7b)
- Budget Committee Minutes, Richmond Area Community Chest (RACC) 1945-1947 (Box 7b)
- Budget Committee Minutes, RACC 1948-1959 (Box 7c)
- Budget Committee Minutes, RACC 1957-1960 (Box 7d)
- Budget Committee 1972 (Box 7d)
- Campaign 1974 (Box 7d)
- Campaign Audits 1974 (Box 7d)
- Campaign Collections 1974-1976 (Box 7d)
- Campaign Complaints 1974 (Box 7d)
- Campaign Publicity 1975 (Box 8)
- Campaign Public Relations 1975 (Box 8)
- Campaign Statistics 1975-1976 (Box 8)
- Campership 1956 (Box 8)
- Camperships 1957-1958 (Box 8)
- Capital Funding Committee 1972 (Box 8)
- Capital Funds Board 1975-1976 (Box 8)
- Capital Funds Statistics 1975-1976 (Box 8)
- Central Richmond Assessment 1981 (Box 8)
- Changing Concepts of the Volunteer Service Bureau 1958-1959 (Box 8)
- Chesterfield Youth Services Commission 1977 (Box 8)
- Christmas 1958-1959 (Box 8)
- Christmas Giving 1957-1958 (Box 8)
- Christmas Giving Study Committee 1957-1958 (Box 8)
- Citizen's Community Study of the Metropolitan Area/Richmond, VA 1974 (Box 8)
- Citizen's Study 1972 (Box 8)
- Citizen's Study Implementation 1975 (Box 9)
- City Strategy Team 1977-1978, 2 folders (Box 9)
- Closing Program 1975 (Box 9)
- Combined Federal Campaign 1974 (Box 9)
- Committee: New Programs/Staff-Study for 1973 Funding 1972 (Box 9)
- Committee On Organization of Social Forces 1939 (Box 9)
- Community Chest 1956 (Box 9)
- Community Chest and Council Bulletins 1956-1957 (Box 9)
- Community Chest and Council "Community" Magazine 1956 (Box 9)
- Community Chest and Council Correspondence 1956-1957 (Box 10)
- Community Chest and Council Materials 1956-1957 (Box 10)
- Community Council (Others) 1956-1957 (Box 10)
- Community Council 1940-1941, 1956-1957 (Box 10)
- Community Council Board of Directors-Minutes 1949-1951 (Box 10)
- Community Council Minutes 1952-1954 (Box 10)
- Community Council Minutes-Board of Directors, Executive Committee, Community Council 1954-1956 (Box 10)
- Community Council Minutes-Board of Directors, Executive Committee, Council Meetings 1956-1963 (Box 11)
- Community Health Survey 1971-1972 (Box 11)
- Community Magazines-United Way of America 1962-1970 (Box 11)
- Community Organization of Social Forces 1939 (Box 11)
- Community Orientation Course for Volunteers 1946 (Box 11)
- Community Resource Committee 1980 (Box 12)
- Community Youth Relations League 1956-1957 (Box 12)
- C on C with C 1956-1957 (Box 12)
- Contributions of Employees in Virginia 1971-1972 (Box 12)
- Corporate 1975 (Box 12)
- Corporate Campaign Kickoffs 1974 (Box 12)
- Corporate Lists (Workers and Assignments) 1975 (Box 12)
- Corporate Section Correspondence 1974 (Box 12)
- Corporate Statistics 1975 (Box 13)
- Correspondence 1976, 1979 (Box 13)
- Correspondence form Frank Cleaver 1962 (Box 13)
- Correspondence with Agencies 1957-1959 (Box 13)
- Correspondence with Chairman-Advisory Committee 1957-1958 (Box 13)
- Correspondence with Chairman-Volunteer Service Bureau 1958-1959 (Box 13)
- Correspondence with Group Volunteers 1956-1958 (Box 13)
- Correspondence with Individual Volunteers 1956-1959 (Box 13)
- Correspondence with Service Bureaus in Other Community Councils 1958-1959 (Box 14)
- Council of Women's Organizations 1956-1957 (Box 14)
- Council Meetings 1966-1970 (Box 14)
- Council Minutes 1970-1974 (Box 14)
- Council of Social Agencies 1916-1921, 1924-1925, 1934 (Box 14)
- Council of Social Agencies-Minutes 1919-1925, 1928-1932 (Box 14)
- Council of Social Agencies-Minutes 1932, 1935-1938 (Box 15)
- Council of Social Workers 1921 (Box 15)
- Council of Social Agencies (Negro Welfare Survey Committee)-Minutes 1929, 1931-1932 (Box 16)
- Court Volunteers 1969 (Box 16)
- De institutionalization: Its Impact on Homes for Adults 1981 (Box 16)
- Deferred Giving 1974 (Box 16)
- Development of Management Assistance Programs 1981 (Box 16)
- Dictionary/Abbreviations-Referral Services 1975 (Box 16)
- Directory of Human Services Organizations (Box 17)
- Driving 1958-1959 (Box 17)
- Electronics Data Processing Committee (EDP) 1976 (Box 17)
- Elizabeth D. Gibble Awards 1968 (Box 17)
- Emergency Food Project 1975 (Box 17)
- Emergency Funding 1982 (Box 17)
- Emergency Housing Services 1982 (Box 17)
- Endowment Fund 1972 (Box 17)
- Estimates and Invoices 1958-1959 (Box 17)
- Executive Committee 1972 (Box 18)
- Executive Newsletter 1962-1967 (Box 18)
- Executive Newsletter 1967-1970 (Box 18)
- Evaluation 1983 (Box 18)
- Evaluation Committee (Box 18)
- Evaluation-Working Papers 1982 (Box 19)
- Filer-Commission 1974-1976 (Box 19)
- Films 1958-1959 (Box 19)
- Finance Committee 1972 (Box 19)
- Form Letters 1979 (Box 19)
- Friendly Visitor Program 1956-1957 (Box 19)
- Friendly Visitors-Miscellaneous 1965-1966 (Box 19)
- Fund Raising Division 1976 (Box 19)
- Gibble, Elizabeth D.-Personal 1959 (Box 20)
- Gibble-Personal 1956-1957 (Box 20)
- Gibble-Talks 1956 (Box 20)
- Girl Scouts 1983 (Box 20)
- Golden WIngs Over Richmond (Steering Committee) 1977-1978 (Box 20)
- Greater Richmond Information-Referral Service Identification System 1975 (Box 20)
- Group Reports-From Volunteer Organizations 1956-1957 (Box 20)
- Handcraft Sale 1956 (Box 20)
- Handicapped Volunteers 1983 (Box 20)
- Hanover County Human Services Committee 1981 (Box 20)
- Hanover County Project 1982 (Box 20)
- Hanover County Services Committee 1972 (Box 20)
- Headquarters Committee 1971 (Box 20)
- Health and Welfare Retirement Committee 1972 (Box 20)
- Health Executive's Roundtable 1978 (Box 20)
- History of the Volunteer Service Bureau 1963-1964 (Box 20)
- History of United Givers Fund (United Way of Greater Richmond) (Box 20)
- Home Care Services 1982 (Box 20)
- Home Health Care 1977 (Box 20)
- Home Health Care Committee 1977 (Box 20)
- Homemaker Services 1980 (Box 20)
- Hospital Orientation Material-Do's and Don't Check Sheets 1956-1957 (Box 20)
- Hospital-Recruitment Orientation 1956-1958 (Box 21)
- Hospital Supervisors 1958-1959 (Box 21)
- Human Services Planning Division 1974-1975 (Box 21)
- Human Services Planning Division 1978 (Box 21)
- Human Services Planning Division 1980-1982 (Box 21)
- Human Services Planning Division-Agency Evaluation Committee 1976, 1978 (Box 21)
- Human Services Planning Division-Agency Evaluation Committee 1980 (Box 22)
- Human Services Planning Division-Board of Trustees 1976, 1976, 1980 (Box 22)
- Human Services Planning Division-Budget and Allocation 1978, 1980 (Box 22)
- Human Services Planning Division-Executive Committee 1976, 1978, 1980 (Box 22)
- Human Services Planning Division-Information and Referral 1976, 1978 (Box 22)
- Human Services Planning Division-Meeting 1980 (Box 22)
- Human Services Planning Division 1975-1980, 9 folders (Box 23)
  Includes meeting notes, minutes, proposals, reports, research and community planning, and 2 files on the voluntary action center
- Ideas for Library 1980 (Box 23)
- Impact of Federal Funding Reductions 1981 (Box 23)
- Information and Referral Staff Applications 1974-1975 (Box 23)
- Information on Member Agencies 1977 (Box 23)
- Instructive Visiting Nurse Association-Evaluation Materials 1976-1980, 8 folders (Box 23)
- Instructive Visiting Nurse Association-Evaluation Materials 1979-1980, 5 folders (Box 24)
- Insurance 1976 (Box 24)
- Intern Selection UWA (Box 24)
- Involvement Corps Program Review Committee 1976 (Box 24)
- Jewish Family Services 1980 (Box 24)
- Jewish Federation Study 1972 (Box 24)
- J. Sergeant Reynolds Community College 1974-1975 (Box 24)
- June Jubilee 1983 (Box 25)
- Junior League 1956-1959, 1982-1983, 5 folders (Box 24)
- Labor Programs 1972 (Box 25)
- Legal Committee 1972 (Box 25)
- Legislation 1974 (Box 25)
- Letters of Support-Cumberland Farms 1977 (Box 25)
- Liability Drivers 1954 (Box 25)
- Life Insurance 1982 (Box 25)
- Lists-Clubs, Churches, Organizations, etc. 1956-1957 (Box 25)
- Literary Program 1983 (Box 25)
- Litter Prevention 1976 (Box 25)
- Logos 1983 (Box 25)
- Long Range Planning 1978-1979, 1982 (Box 25)
- Mail Out 1978 (Box 25)
- Manual of Policies and Procedures (UWGR) 1979 (Box 25)
- Material for Recruitment Training, etc 1956 (Box 25)
- Maymont Garden Market 1983 (Box 25)
- Day Care Alternatives 1982-1983 (Box 25)
- Memos-To and From Barbara Wyatt 1982 (Box 25)
- Mental Health 1979 (Box 25)
- Mental Health Association of Richmond 1956-1957 (Box 25)
- Mental Health/Mental Retardation Project 1977-1978, 1980, 14 folders (Box 26)
- Mental Health Sub Committee 1979-1980, 6 folders (Box 26)
- Metro II Cities (YMCA Funding)-Questionnaire 1976 (Box 27)
- Minutes of Board of Directors (1-209) 1940-1949 (Box 27)
- Miscellaneous 1956-1958 (Box 27)
- Miscellaneous File 1972 (Box 27)
- Miscellaneous Solicitors 1975 (Box 27)
- Model Cities, Inc. 1967-1968 (Box 27)
- Monthly Hours 1982-1983 (Box 27)
- Monthly Statistics 1982 (Box 27)
- National Association of Social Workers 1956-1957 (Box 28)
- National Center for Voluntary Action-Bulletins 1973 (Box 28)
- National Child Immunization Campaign 1977 (Box 28)
- National Standards-Information and Referral Services 1973 (Box 28)
- Newpol, Leo 1972 (Box 28)
- New Programs and Positions 1972, 2 folders (Box 28)
- Newsletter 1972 (Box 28)
- Newspaper Articles-for Scrapbook 1968 (Box 28)
- Nominating Committee 1970-1973 (Box 28)
- Nominating Committee 1975-1977 (Box 28)
- Nominating Committee 1981 (Box 28)
- Nominations for the Elizabeth Gibble Award 1972 (Box 28)
- Oldsters 1957-1959 (Box 29)
- Orders-Agency (Volunteer's Hour Cards) 1956-1957 (Box 29)
- Orientation Manual (UGWR) 1980 (Box 29)
- Personnel 1972 (Box 29)
- Personnel Committee 1972 (Box 29)
- Personnel Development UWA 1975-1976 (Box 29)
- Personnel File (UGF) 1974-1975 (Box 29)
- Personnel Practices Committee 1969 (Box 29)
- Personnel-Resumes 1974-1976 (Box 29)
- Policy and Development Issues-General Information 1979 (Box 29)
- Policy Planning-Priorities 1982 (Box 29)
- Pre-Campaign Receipts-Corporate and Special 1975 (Box 29)
- Priorities 1979 (Box 30)
- Priorities 1980 (Box 30)
- Priorities Implementation Review Committee Report 1981 (Box 30)
- Proceeding of Association of Volunteer Bureaus, Inc. 1976 (Box 30)
- Professional Advisory Committee 1972-1976 (Box 30)
- Professional Openings 1956-1957 (Box 30)
- Program Development (Future) 1983 (Box 30)
- Program for the Future UWA 1976 (Box 30)
- Program Report (Box 30)
- Programs Recommended for Funding 1981 (Box 30)
- Projects-Christmas 1956 (Box 31)
- Projects-Terminated 1956-1957 (Box 31)
- Projects Suggestions 1956-1957 (Box 31)
- Proposed Budgets 1981 (Box 31)
- Publications Catalog 1976 (Box 31)
- Public Policy Committee 1980 (Box 31)
- Public Policy Sub Committee 1979 (Box 31)
- Public Relations 1973 (Box 31)
- Public Relations Committee 1973-1976 (Box 31)
- Questionnaire-Nepotism 1975 (Box 32)
- RACC Summer Youth Program 1968 (Box 32)
- Rasim Kassem Correspondence 1979-1980, 2 folders (Box 32)
- Readers for the Blind 1956-1957 (Box 32)
- Recognition (Box 32)
- Recognition 1982 (Box 33)
- Record of Volunteer Hours 1943 (Box 33)
- Recreation and Group Work Executives Roundtables 1978 (Box 33)
- Recreation and Group Work Executives Roundtables/Health Executives 1977 (Box 33)
- Recreation Recruitment Orientation-Group Workers 1957-1958 (Box 33)
- Recruitment 1956-1957 (Box 33)
- Referral Systems 1975 (Box 33)
- Refugee Volunteers 1983 (Box 33)
- Regional Resource Team 1977-1979, 4 folders (Box 33)
- Report Meetings 1975 (Box 34)
- Report of Budget and Allocations Committee 1981-1982 (Box 34)
- Report on New Funding-Agency Evaluation Committee 1980-1981 (Box 34)
- Reports-Monthly 1956-1959 (Box 34)
- Reports of Hours from Volunteers 1958-1959 (Box 34)
- Report to Executive Committee on Future of Volunteer Service Bureau 1957-1958 (Box 34)
- Research and Community Planning 1978 (Box 34)
- Research and Community Planning Committee 1979-1980 (Box 34)
- Research and Community Planning Committee Agendas 1982 (Box 34)
- Research and Community Planning Committee Minutes 1982 (Box 34)
- Research and Community Planning Committee Papers 1979 (Box 34)
- Research and Community Planning Committee Project Report 1981 (Box 35)
- Research and Community Planning Committee Roster (Box 35)
- Research Committee 1976 (Box 35)
- Retired Senior Volunteer Program (RSVP) 1976 (Box 35)
- Retirement Committee 1972 (Box 35)
- Retirement Questionnaire 1976 (Box 35)
- Review Report-United Way National Attitude Survey 1976 (Box 35)
- Richmond Area Community Chest Red Feather Award1949 (Box 35)
- Richmond Area Community Council 1967-1968, 2 folders (Box 35)
- Richmond Area Community Council (1 of 2) 1969-1970 (Box 35)
- Richmond Area Community Council (2 of 2) 1969-1970 (Box 36)
- Richmond Community Mental Health, etc 1972 (Box 36)
- Richmond Council of Women's Organizations 1967-1968 (Box 36)
- Richmond Urban League 1957, 1965-1966, 3 folders (Box 36)
- Richmond Urban League-Miscellaneous 1965 (Box 36)
- Richmond Urban League-Newspaper Clippings 1968 (Box 36)
- Rosters 1972 (Box 36)
- Round Table Discussion 1981 (Box 36)
- Salute 1959, 1968 (Box 37)
- Salute-List of Cards Made 1957 (Box 37)
- Salute to Volunteers 1957-1958 (Box 37)
- Scholarship (Guideline and Applications) 1971-1977 (Box 37)
- Secretary's Report as Given at Advisory Committee Meetings 1956-1957 (Box 37)
- Service Profile-Community Health Services 1979 (Box 37)
- Service Profile-Crime and Delinquency Prevention Services 1979 (Box 37)
- Service Profile-Family Preservation and Strengthening Services 1979 (Box 37)
- Service Profile-Social Planning Services 1979 (Box 37)
- Service Profile-Transportation Services 1979 (Box 37)
- Services Identification System-UGWR 1981 (Box 37)
- Slide Presentation 1982 (Box 37)
- Social Indicatory Newsletter 1977 (Box 37)
- Social Security Amendment (Title XX) 1975-1976 (Box 38)
- Social Work-Case Council 1936-1939 (Box 38)
- Special Gifts 1974-1975 (Box 38)
- Special Services 1956-1957 (Box 38)
- Spot Workers 1956-1959, 3 folders (Box 38)
- Springboard-Planning for Community Center in Bainbridge 1977 (Box 38)
- Staff 1972 (Box 38)
- Staff Memos 1974-1976 (Box 38)
- Staff Orientation 1957-1958 (Box 38)
- Staff Retirement 1970-1977 (Box 38)
- Staff Time Study 1976 (Box 38)
- Standards of Excellence 1974 (Box 38)
- Statement of Personnel Policies and Practices 1977 (Box 38)
- Statistics 1968 (Box 38)
- Stock Gifts to United Way 1976-1977 (Box 38)
- Study-Volunteer Services Bureau 1957-1958 (Box 38)
- Suggestions (Staff) 1976 (Box 39)
- Survey and Feasibility Planning Study of Physical Facilities for the United Givers Fund of Richmond, Henrico, Chesterfield, Inc. March 1969, August 1969, October 1969, 3 folders (Box 39)
- Teamwork-Material 1956-1957 (Box 39)
- Technical Assistance 1981 (Box 39)
- Teenage Program 1960-1961 (Box 39)
- Teenage Recognition Party 1967 (Box 39)
- Teenage Volunteers-Recognition 1968-1969 (Box 39)
- Teenage Youth 1968 (Box 39)
- Thalhimer's Window 1966-1968 (Box 39)
- Thank you Letters 1956-1957 (Box 39)
- Thank you Letters 1957-1958 (Box 39)
- The Board and Its Responsibilities 1979 (Box 39)
- The Future of Volunteerism: Meeting Changing Societal Needs 1979 (Box 40)
- The Salvation Army-Budget 1981 (Box 40)
- The University of Virginia Newsletter 1980 (Box 40)
- The Voluntary Action Center-Manual 1977 (Box 40)
- Time and Place Committee 1975 (Box 40)
- Title XX Needs Assessment 1977 (Box 40)
- Transportation 1981 (Box 40)
- Transportation Sub Committee 1979 (Box 40)
- Traweek, Jean 1972 (Box 40)
- Trustees 1980 (Box 40)
- United Community Funds and Councils 1958-1959 (Box 40)
- United Givers Fund-Minutes (Finance Committee) January-December 1970 (Box 40)
- United Way Corporate Giving Seminar 1976 (Box 40)
- United Way-Manpower Advisory Committee 1975 (Box 40)
- United Way-NBA and NFL Promotion 1976 (Box 40)
- United Way of America 1972-1977, 7 folders (Box 41)
- United Way of Greater Richmond 1974-1975 (Box 41)
- United Way of Greater Richmond-General Information 1975 (Box 42)
- United Way of Greater Richmond-Minutes, Agendas and Reports of the Research and Community Planning Committee 1980 (Box 42)
- University of Richmond 1983 (Box 42)
- Update of Research and Community Planning Projects 1980 (Box 42)
- UWA-Community Campaign 1974-1975 (Box 42)
- UWASIS and Its Uses 1975 (Box 42)
- UWASIS-People and Programs Need Uniform and Comparable Definitions 1972 (Box 42)
- VAC United Way of Staff-Brainstorm Sessions 1978 (Box 42)
- VCU-Adjunct Faculty 1974-1976 (Box 42)
- VCU-Class (Administration) 1975-1976 (Box 43)
- Virginia Chapter-Arthritis and Rheumatism Foundation 1958 (Box 43)
- Virginia Conference of Social Work-Board 1956-1957 (Box 43)
- Virginia Conference of Social Work-Committee for Cooperation with Community Organizations 1956-1957 (Box 43)
- Virginia Purchase of Service Manual 1975, n.d., 7 folders (Box 43)
- Virginia Textiles 1982 (Box 43)
- Voluntary Action Center Committee-Meetings 1978 (Box 43)
- Voluntary Action Center 1974, 1975, 1978, 3 folders (Box 43)
- Volunteer Administration-Summer 1977 (Box 44)
- Volunteer Administration-Fall 1977 (Box 44)
- Volunteer Administration-Winter 1978 (Box 44)
- Volunteer Administration-Summer 1979 (Box 44)
- Volunteer and Staff Responsibilities 1979 (Box 44)
- Volunteer Bureau's Bulletins 1956-1957 (Box 44)
- Volunteer in Service to America-Training 1982 (Box 44)
- Volunteer Motivation and Need Fulfillment in an Instrumental Voluntary Association 1977 (Box 44)
- Volunteer of the Month 1967-1968 (Box 44)
- Volunteer Roundup 1958-1959 (Box 44)
- Volunteer Service Bureau 1957-1966 (Box 45)
- Volunteer Service Bureau 1967-1968 (Box 45)
- Volunteer Service Bureau-Advisory Committee Minutes 1957-1960 (Box 45)
- Volunteer Service Bureau-Advisory Committee (Orientation Kit) 1959-1960 (Box 45)
- Volunteer Service Bureau-Annual Report 1956-1957 (Box 45)
- Volunteer Service Bureau Manual-Office Procedure 1965 (Box 45)
- Volunteer Service Bureau-Minutes 1942, 1965-1975 (Box 45)
- Volunteer Service Bureau-Miscellaneous 1961-1967 (Box 45)
- Volunteer Service Bureaus and Other Community Councils 1956-1957 (Box 45)
- Volunteer Service Bureaus Association 1956-1957 (Box 45)
- Volunteer Service Bureaus-Correspondence 1957-1958 (Box 46)
- Volunteer Service 1949 (Box 45)
- Volunteer Service Bureaus-Southeastern District 1957-1958 (Box 45)
- Volunteer Service Bureau Study Committee 1957-1958 (Box 45)
- Volunteer Service Bureau-Vice Chairman of South Eastern District 1956-1957 (Box 46)
- Volunteer Service Bureau-Work Shop 1956-1958 (Box 46)
- Volunteers in Service to America 1982 (Box 46)
- Volunteer Training Course 1948 (Box 46)
- Volunteer Viewpoint 1956-1957 (Box 46)
- Welfare Reform Study Options 1977 (Box 47)
- Work Plan 1979 (Box 47)
- Work Plan 1982 (Box 47)
- Year-Round Cultivation Committee 1974 (Box 47)
- Young Volunteers in Action 1982 (Box 47)